Justin Paul Graber

Senior Software Developer

CONTACT

- (816) 588-9860
- 4graber@protonmail.com
- Kansas
- www.jgraber.me

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Engineering Physics

Missouri State University Springfield, MO | 2010

Master's in Computer Science

University of Missouri - Kansas City | in-progress

Programming Languages

Javascript, Typescript, Node JS, Python, Golang, Bash

Databases

PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Redis, MongoDB, Snowflake

Architecture

AWS Lambda, AWS Kinesis Data Streams, Nginx, Apache Kafka, Docker, Micro-Service Architecture

PROFILE

I work as a senior backend and data engineer with 10 years of experience building and maintaining application software. I have a passion for solving fun and challenging problems and enjoy learning new technology. I earned a Bachelor's degree in Physics and a minor in Mathematics.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Backend Software Engineer

Ready Responders | New Orleans, LA, | 2021-PRESENT

Ready is a healthcare company that sends providers into patient's homes to provide in-person health services. While at Ready, I worked as a senior backend engineer to help design and build their 2.0 EMR data model and GraphQl API from the ground up.

- Helped lead the effort to design and implement the 2.0 EHR relational data model using PostgreSQL.
- Worked with multiple other developers to build the core GraphQl API using Node JS, Typescript and Postgraphile.
- Led a project to migrate existing legacy health data from a DynamoDB data store to relational PostgreSQL model using AWS Lambda, Kinesis, Apache Airflow, and DBT data transformations..
- Developed several microservices using Golang / Python and Node to integrate with third party APIs such as Zoom and others.

Senior Data Engineer

EquipmentShare | Kansas City, MO | 2020 - 2021

As a Senior Data Engineer at EquipmentShare my primary responsibility was to build and support our main data warehouse which was Snowflake. I helped architect and build a real-time streaming pipeline using AWS Kinesis Data Streams and AWS Lambda functions to stream billions of records into Snowflake.

- Implemented a data streaming pipeline using technologies such as Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and AWS Lambda.
- Helped to build a data transformation layer using Python services.
- Was responsible for monitoring and maintaining the health and performance of the data warehouse and pipeline.
- Helped to increase SQL performance and efficiency.

Web Technologies

REST, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS3, React, Angular JS, Redux, D3, Flask

References

Tony Marhsall President & CTO

Dunami, Inc. 913.961.7731

Nate Dean Director of Application Development

SelectQuote. 816.729.2696

Aaron Brooks Big Data Architect

Imply.io 913.625.2487

Daniel Schimpfoessl Senior Specialist Solutions Architect

Red Hat 913.708.4108

Senior Software Engineer

Dunami, Inc. | Overland Park, Kansas | 2015 - 2020

Dunami is a real-time data analytics company that focuses on network relationship analysis with several patented mathematical algorithms for finding influencers. As a full-stack developer at Dunami, I worked as the team lead for the presentation team, which is responsible for building and maintaining all the user-facing applications as well as the APIs and middleware services that support the data needs of those applications. Specifically, we have built and maintained several single page applications written in React and Angular and a variety of Node.js services that provide the data contracts for these applications.

As the presentation team lead, I managed other team members and developed /

implemented the front-end architecture for several large single page applications.

- Worked as a frontend engineer to develop highly sophisticated web applications using AngularJS and React/Redux.
- I was responsible for building multiple interactive data visualizations using CSS, HTML5, and D3.
- I was responsible for developing a GraphQL API using Node JS.
- I worked with my other team members to develop a Node.js microservice architecture to serve the data contracts for our single page applications.
- I developed / published / maintained multiple NPM modules for collaborative use around our organization.

Software Developer

Keyhole Software | Leawood, Kansas | 2014 - 2015

During my time at Keyhole Software, I worked for several clients as a full stack web application developer. I participated in developer cutting edge applications using Node.js, Backbone JS, Angular JS, Mongo, Redis and Socket.io.

- Planned, architected and developed multiple web applications with diverse stack requirements and client expectations.
- Owned several JavaScript single-page web applications using different front-end frameworks.
- Developed and maintained highly-performant RESTful APIs with Node.js.
- Worked as a technical architect to oversee the implementation of reference architecture for multiple teams.

Software Developer

Ad Astra Information System | Overland Park, Kansas | 2012 - 2014

I began at Ad Astra as a summer intern and was converted to full-time at the end of the internship. While at Ad Astra I helped to maintain a legacy .NET application, as well as implementing and improving core analytical algorithms.

- Developed high quality code in a professional environment.
- Worked to enhance the design and functionality of a web based,

- Single-Page Application using JavaScript and Ext JS.
- Worked to improve stability and performance in sophisticated back-end systems.
- Contributed extensively to refactoring database systems and SQL stored procedures for performance increases.
- Collaborated with developers and product managers to provide creative and innovative solutions for clients.
- Lead a research project for the conversion of Ext JS 3.x to Ext JS 4.x.